In this video, we're going to continue our discussion of the construction of
在这段视频中，我们将继续讨论
[laugh](1) parsing tables by taking a look at how we build the follow sets. So here's
[笑](1)通过查看我们如何构建以下集合来解析表。所以这里是
the definition of follow of x, and recall that the follow set for a given symbol in
x的跟随的定义，并回想一下中给定符号的跟随集
the grammar isn't really about what that symbol can generate, really, doesn't
语法实际上不是关于符号可以生成什么，真的，不是
depend necessarily at all on what the symbol can generate. It depends on where
必须完全依赖于符号可以生成的内容。这取决于在哪里
that symbol can appear, where that symbol is used in the grammar. And we say that t
该符号可以出现，在语法中使用该符号。我们说t
is in the follow of x if there is some place in the grammar, some derivation,
在x后面，如果在语法中有某个位置，一些派生，
where that terminal t can appear immediately after the symbol x. Okay, so
其中终端T可以紧跟在符号x之后。好，所以
for all such. E. They make up the follow set of x. And here's some intuition about
为了所有这些。即它们组成了下面的x集合。这里有一些关于
how we would compute follow sets. Let's say we have a situation where X goes to
我们将如何计算跟随集。假设我们有这样一种情况，X去了
two symbols A, B, right? And then anything that B can produce in the first position
两个符号A，B，对吗？然后B在第一个位置能产生的任何东西
will clearly be in the follow of A. So if we have X goes to AB. And then through
很明显在A的后面，所以如果我们有X，就去AB。然后穿过
some more, steps, we can get something like, this A goes, B goes to T beta, then
更多的步骤，我们可以得到这样的结果，这个A是这样的，B是Tβ，然后是Tβ
we have a situation where the T comes immediately after the A, and so clearly,
我们有一种情况，T紧跟在A之后，所以很明显，
something that was in the first of B, is in the follow of A. So, so the basic rule
B的第一个部分，在A的后面，所以基本规则是
is that you have two symbols that are adjunct somewhere, the first of the second
你有两个符号在某个地方是附加的，第二个符号中的第一个
one is in the follow of the first one. Hm, now Another interesting effect here is
一个在第一个之后。嗯，现在另一个有趣的效果是
that, if we have, a symbol at the end of a production. Let's take a look at the B
那就是，如果我们有的话，在一部作品的结尾会有一个符号。我们来看一下B
here for a moment, okay? And a claim here that anything that's in the follow of the
在这里待一会儿，好吗？这里有一种说法，那就是紧随其后的任何东西
left hand side is gonna be in the follow of B. In this case, that the follow of X
左手边将在B的后面。在这种情况下，X的后面
is a subset of the follow of B. And let's take a look at that. Let's say that we
是B后面的子集，让我们来看看。比方说，我们
have, a situation where we have a derivation from the start symbol, okay? We
有一种情况，我们有一个从开始符号派生出来的情况，好吗？我们
wind up with X followed by T. It can, it can be other stuff around the [inaudible]
以X结尾，然后是T。它可以，它可以是[听不见]周围的其他东西
let's ignore that for the moment, let's just focus on the XT. Then we can use this
让我们暂时忽略这一点，让我们只关注XT。那我们就可以用这个
production X goes to AB and in one step we can get to ABT. And then we see T was in
生产X转到AB，我们只需一步就能到达ABT。然后我们看到T在
the follow of X a nd also, T is in the follow of B as a result, Okay. So,
跟在X后面的还有，T跟在B后面，好的。所以,
anything in the follow of X would also be in the follow of B. And we can generalize
任何跟在X后面的东西都会跟在B后面，我们可以推广
this observation about what occurs at the end of a production. So anything that
关于制作结束时发生的事情的观察。所以任何可以
occurs at the end of the production, it, its follow set will include the follow set
在生产结束时发生，它它的跟随集将包括以下集
of the symbol on the left hand side of the production. Well, what is the end of the
作品左手边的符号。那么，这场比赛的结局是什么呢？
production? If, if B can go to epsilon, if B can disappear, then A will appear at the
制作？如果，如果B可以去ε，如果B可以消失，那么A将出现在
end of the production. Okay, so if B can go to epsilon, then it will also happen
制作结束了。好的，如果B可以去epsilon，那么它也会发生
that the follow of X, would be in the follow of A. And following up here in our
X的后边会是A的后边，在我们的
example, so we. Or up here we start with the start symbol. We got to XT. In one
举个例子，所以我们。或者在这里，我们从开始符号开始。我们到了XT。合二为一
step we got to ABT and so T was in the follow of B. But now, B can go into
我们到了ABT，所以T紧跟在B之后，但是现在，B可以进入
epsilon and so we can also get to AT and therefore T is also in the follow of A.
Epsilon，所以我们也可以得到AT，因此T也在A之后。
And finally there's one special case. Remember that we have our special symbol
最后还有一个特例。记住我们有我们的特殊标志
marking the end of the input, and what can that follow? Well the end of the input is
标记输入的结束，那么接下来会发生什么呢？好的，输入的末尾是
in the follow of the start symbol, alright? And this is just a way again of
在开始符号后面，好吗？这只是一种再一次
keeping track of what we're going to do when we run out of input. And we'll see
记录我们在输入耗尽时要做的事情。我们将拭目以待
how that's used when we built the parsing tables but we always add as an initial
我们在构建解析表时如何使用它，但我们总是将其作为首字母添加
condition, that dollar sign is in the follow of the start symbol. So now, let's
条件下，美元符号在开始符号后面。所以现在，让我们
take a look at and sketch of the algorithm for computing follows. So that's, as we
下面来看一下计算算法的草图。所以这就是，因为我们
just said, the dollar sign is in the follow of the start symbol. And now we
刚才说了，美元符号在开始符号后面。现在我们
take a look at each production. Okay, A goes to alpha X beta, we're, we're
看一看每一部作品。好的，A去阿尔法X贝塔，我们是，我们是
focusing here on the X. Okay, if we look at every production and we look at every
把焦点集中在X。好的，如果我们看每一部作品，我们看每一部
symbol on the right hand side of that production. And the first of beta, okay,
作品右手边的符号。第一个测试版，好的，
the thing that can follow x in this in this production, the first of that will be
在这部作品中，可以跟在x后面的是，第一个
in the follow of x, and also we just subtract out epsilon if it was in the
在x后面，如果ε在x后面，我们就减去ε
first sub-beta. We're not interested anymore in the epsilons for the purposes
第一次亚贝塔测试。我们对爱西隆不再感兴趣了
of follow sites, epsilon never appears in follow sites, so follow sites are always
在关注站点中，epsilon从未出现在关注站点中，因此关注站点总是
just sets of terminals. And now the second part of the algorithm is it if we have
只有几组终端。现在算法的第二部分是，如果我们有
some suffix of a production beta that can go to Epsilon, so Epsilon is in the first
生产测试版的一些后缀，可以到Epsilon，所以Epsilon是第一个
beta. Alright, this suffix of the production can completely disappear, then
贝塔。好的，那么制作的这个后缀就可以完全消失了。
as we saw on the previous slide the follow of left hand side symbol will be in the
正如我们在上一张幻灯片中看到的，下面的左侧符号将位于
follow of X. And that's it in terms of the rules for computing follow sets. So now
跟在X后面，这就是计算跟随集的规则。所以现在
let's work through an example. So here's our grammar again. And we're going to
让我们通过一个例子来了解一下。所以我们的语法又来了。我们要做的就是
compute, the follow sets for each of the symbols of the grammar. So let's begin,
计算语法中每个符号的以下集合。那么让我们开始吧，
with the, with the start symbol. We'll start with the follow of E. And by
带，带开始符号。我们将从E的后面开始，然后到
definition, we know that dollar is in the follow of E. So we get that one easily.
定义，我们知道美元跟在E后面，所以我们很容易得到它。
And now the question is what else could be in the follow of E, Alright? So in order
现在的问题是E后面还有什么，好吗？所以按照顺序
to figure that out we have to look at where E is used in the grammar, Alright?
要弄清楚这一点，我们必须看一下E在语法中的位置，好吗？
So remember always at follow sets are about where the symbol is used. Not what
所以请记住，始终在后面的集合是关于符号的使用位置。不是什么
it produces. Alright? So here. Is a place where E is used, and we can see that it is
它会产生。好吗？所以这里。是一个使用E的地方，我们可以看到它是
merely followed by a terminal symbol, so certainly close paren is in the follow of
后面只跟了一个终端符号，所以Close Paren肯定跟在
E, right? And there's one other place where E is used, and that's over here. And
E，对吗？还有一个地方用到了E，那就是这里。和
it appears that the right end of the production, and so then we know that
看起来是制作的正确结尾，所以我们知道
anything that's in the follow of X is also gonna be in the follow of E. And that's a
任何跟在X后面的东西都会跟在E后面，那就是a
constraint, and so we'll right that down over here 'coz this is just a property of
约束，所以我们会把它放在这里，因为这只是
the relationship. That the follow sets, will have when we're done computing them.
这段关系。当我们完成计算后，下面的集合就会有。
This doesn't immediately tell us anything new that's in the follow of E. But we know
这不会立即告诉我们跟在E后面的任何新情况，但我们知道
that as we go along, and we learn about things that are in the follow of X, we'll
在我们前进的过程中，我们了解了X后面的东西，我们将
have to add them to the follow of E. And let me just divide up. The slide here so
我要把它们加到E的后面，让我把它们分开。这里的幻灯片是这样的
we will put our properties that we know about relationships between fallocates
我们将把我们知道的关于错位之间关系的属性
over on the left hand side and we'll put the actual fallocates over here on the
在左手边，我们会把实际的错误放在这里
right side. So, now to make, that's the only two places, those are the only two pl
右边。所以，现在要做的是，这是唯一的两个地方，那是唯一的两个地方
aces where E is used in the grammar and to make further progress we need to know
E在语法中的用法是ACES，为了取得进一步的进步，我们需要知道
something about the follow of X. Okay, if we want to make further progress on the
关于X的后续内容。好的，如果我们想要在
follow of E then we need to figure out what's in the follow of X. So, let's focus
跟在E后面，然后我们需要弄清楚跟在X后面的是什么。所以，让我们集中注意力
on that for a minute. So, where's X used in the grammar, well it's used in only one
想一想这件事。那么，X在语法中的用法是什么，它只用在一个
place and that's here, Okay? Where it appears at the right end of a production.
就在这里，好吗？它出现在一部作品的右端。
And what, and so therefore, the symbol on the left hand side will be a subset of the
因此，左手边的符号将是
follow set of X. So we're gonna know that the follow of E is a subset of the follow
跟随X的集合。所以我们将知道E的跟随是下面的子集
of X. Alright? And what does that mean? Well, so follow of X is a subset of follow
关于X的，好吗？那是什么意思？那么，X的Follow是Follow的子集
of E. And follow of E is a subset of the follow of X. So that really means that
E的后跟是X的后跟的子集，所以这实际上意味着
these two sets are equal. The follow of X and the follow of E, whatever they wind up
这两套是相等的。X跟在后面，E跟在后面，不管它们以什么结尾
being, are gonna have to be the same set. And now we've looked at all the places
必须是同一套。现在我们已经看过了所有的地方
where E is used in the grammar. We've looked at all the places where X is used
其中E用在语法中。我们看过所有使用X的地方
in the grammar. We can't learn anything more about what is in the sets, the follow
在语法上。我们不能更多地了解布景里有什么，下面是
sets of E and X. We're not forced to add anything else, to either set, and so we're
E和X的集合。我们没有被强迫添加任何其他的东西，对这两个集合中的任何一个，所以我们
done. And so we can close off this set. And we know the follow of E consists of
好了。这样我们就可以关闭这个布景了。我们知道E的后面是由
dollar sign and closed paren. And we also know that X. Has the same set, the same
美元符号和闭合的帕伦。我们也知道X有相同的集合，相同的集合
follow set. Alright, so now let's move on to the follow of T, All right. So what's
跟随SET。好的，现在让我们继续T的后面，好的。那么什么是
going to be in the follow of T? Well we, again we have to look at where T is used
会追随T的脚步吗？那么我们，我们还是要看看T在哪里用的
in the grammar. So T is used in two places. The first one is here in the first
在语法上。所以T用在两个地方。第一个在这里，在第一个
production. And so what's going to be in the follow of T? Well it could be anything
制作。那么T之后会是什么呢？嗯，它可以是任何东西。
that is in the first of X. Okay? Cuz X comes immediately after T. And if you
那是在X的第一个，好吗？因为X紧跟在T之后，如果你
recall from the previous video, there were only two things in the first of X. One was
回想上一段视频，X的第一部分只有两样东西，一是
plus. So this plus is definitely in the follow of T and let's just review. [cough]
另外。所以这个加号肯定在T后面，我们来复习一下。[咳嗽]
Excuse me. How that can happen, so we can go from E. To TX, okay? I'm using the
打扰了。怎么会这样，这样我们就可以从东部到德克萨斯州了，好吗？我正在使用
first production. And now we see the X comes after the T. And then in one more
第一部作品。现在我们看到X在T之后，然后再加一个
step, we can go to T plus E. And now we have a derivation where plus follows T.
我们可以转到T+E，现在我们有一个导数，其中+跟在T后面。
And that's how we, that's, that's Y pluses in the follow of T. Alright? So the other
这就是我们，也就是T后面的Y加号，好吗？所以另一个
thing that was in the first of X was epsilon, because there's an epsilon
X的第一个部分是ε，因为有一个epsilon
production for X over here. But remember that we're not interested in, we don't
在这里为X制作。但请记住，我们对此不感兴趣，我们不会
include epsilon in follow sets. And so X doesn't contribute anything else, to the,
将epsilon包括在以下集合中。所以X没有贡献任何其他的东西，
to the follow of T. But since X can go to epsilon, remember what that means. That
跟在T后面，但既然X可以到ε，记住这是什么意思。那
means that over here, looking back at this first use of T again in the grammar, this
意思是，在这里，再回顾一下T在语法中的第一次使用，这
X can disappear. Right and that means that anything it is in the follow of E is also
X可以消失。对，这意味着它跟在E后面的任何东西也是
in the follow of T. Now we already know the follow of E. So we can just add those
现在我们已经知道了E的后缀，所以我们只需添加这些
things in. Okay? And let me write that down over here, just so that we don't
东西都进来了。好吧?让我把它写在这里，这样我们就不会
forget it. So, to follow. Of, of E is a subset of the follow of T. We won't really
休想。所以，接下来。of，of E是T后面的一个子集。我们不会真的
need this fact again but, useful to write it down, perhaps. Alright and now we are
我需要再次了解这个事实，但是，也许把它写下来会很有用。好的，现在我们是
done with this use of x. We've included everything implied by this production that
已经完成了x的这个用法。我们已经包含了这个结果所暗示的所有
we can in the follow of T and so now have to look at the other place where T is used
我们可以跟在T后面，所以现在必须看一下使用T的另一个地方
and that's over here. Okay, and so here we're going to see that T is in the right
那就是这里。好的，这里我们将看到T是正确的
end of a production, so anything that is in the follow Y can also be in the follow
产品的结束，所以后面的Y中的任何东西也可以在下面
of T, alright? So the follow of Y. Is going to be a subset of the follow of T,
关于T的，好吗？所以Y的后跟将是T的后跟的子集，
alright. So now we can go off and work on the follow of Y. We have to in order to
好的。所以现在我们可以出发去做Y的后续工作了。我们必须这样做，以便
figure out what the follow of T is going to be, we're gonna have to know the follow
算出后面的T是什么，我们必须知道下面的
of Y. So where is Y used in the grammar? Well there is only one place and that's
那么Y在语法中用在哪里呢？嗯，只有一个地方，那就是
over here. And also Y appears in the right hand of production which means that the
在这里。Y也出现在产品的右手边，这意味着
left hand side symbol it's follow set will be included in the follow of Y. >> And so
左手边符号它的跟随集将包含在Y>>的后面，依此类推
the follow of t will be a subset of the follow of y. All right? And now again, we
t后面的是y后面的子集，好吗？现在又一次，我们
have two follow sets that are subsets of each other. Follow of y is a subset of
有两个相互为子集的跟随集。跟在y后面的是的子集
follow of t, and follow of t is a subset of follow of y. And so these two sets, we
跟在t后面，跟在t后面是跟在y后面的子集，所以这两个集合，我们
know are going to have to be equal. Okay? So we can write down here. At the follow
必须是相等的。好吧?这样我们就可以在这里写下来了。在以下位置
of Y, includes plus, dollar, enclose parette. Just like the follow of T. And
的，包括加号、美元、包含Parette。就像T和
now we're done. We've, we've, follow of T, and follow of Y. We've followed all the
现在我们做完了。我们，我们跟着T，跟着Y。我们跟着所有的
implications of, how the follow of T gets things into, what can be included in the
的含义，下面的T是如何把东西放进去的，什么可以包含在
follow of T. We've worked out all the places where Y is used in the grammar, and
跟在T后面。我们已经算出了Y在语法中用的所有地方，还有
added all the things that we can, based on, it's context. And there's nothing more
根据它的背景，添加了我们能做的所有事情。没有什么比这更多了
that we're forced to add either said. So we can go ahead and close these sets off.
我们不得不加上这两个词中的任何一个。这样我们就可以继续关闭这些布景了。
They're finished, Alright. So now We've done the follow of E, X, T, and Y. So
他们做完了，好的。现在我们已经完成了E、X、T和Y的操作。
we've taken care of all the terminal symbols. But, I'm sorry, All the
我们已经处理了所有的终端符号。但是，我很抱歉，所有的
non-terminal symbols. But we still need to compute the follow sets for the terminal
非端子符号。但是我们仍然需要为终端计算以下集合
symbols. And unlike the case with first sets, the follow sets for terminal symbols
符号。与第一个集合的情况不同，端子符号的以下集合
can actually be interesting. So let's take a look, at the follow of open paren. Okay,
可能真的会很有趣。那么让我们来看一看，下面是开放的帕伦。好吧,
what can follow an open paren in a derivation? Well open paren is only used
派生中可以跟随开放Paren的是什么？嗯，敞开的帕伦只用来
in one places. It's here. Okay. And so, what can follow in open parens is whatever
在一个地方。就在这里。好吧。因此，左括号中可以跟的内容是
is in the first of E. And remember that the first of E, was the same as the first
是在E的第一个，记住E的第一个和第一个是一样的
of T, because T always produces something in the first position. And the first of T
因为T总是在第一个位置产生一些东西。和T的第一个
was what? It was open paren. An int, 'kay? And if you think about this for a minute,
是什么？是敞开的，帕伦。一个整数，好吗？如果你想一分钟，
this makes complete sense. What can come after an at any valid, at any valid string
这完全有道理。在任何有效的、任何有效的字符串的at后面可以出现什么
in this grammar, while it's going to be another nested parenthize expression, or
在此语法中，虽然它将是另一个嵌套的括号表达式，或者
is it going to be an integer. In particular, you couldn't have a times or a
它会是一个整数吗。尤其是，你不能有一次或一次
plus immediately after an and you couldn't absolutely have the end of the input, you
加上紧接在输入之后，您不能绝对结束输入，您可以
couldn't have the input stop after an and have a valid string. So now let's take a
不能让输入在后停止，并且具有有效字符串。所以现在让我们来看一看
look at the follow of. Okay? So what's in that set? Again, we look at where the
请看下面的……好吧?那套里面有什么？再一次，我们来看一下
symbol is used. It's only used here, in this one production. So and, because it
使用符号。它只在这里使用，在这一部作品中使用。所以，因为它
appears at the right end of the production, we know that whatever is in
出现在制作的正确末端，我们知道无论里面是什么
the follow of T is going to be in the follow of ), all right. And so what was in
T的后面是)，好的。那么里面有什么呢？
the follow of T, [cough], that was +$), Okay. So, now let's move on and take a
T后面，[咳]，就是+$)，好的。那么，现在让我们继续，让我们来看一看
look at the operators. Let's look at the follow of plus. So where's plus used?
看看操作员。让我们看看下面的加号。那么PLUS在哪里用呢？
Well, it's only used here. So whatever's in the first of E is going to be in the
嗯，它只在这里用。所以无论E的第一个字母是什么，都会出现在字母E的第一个字母中
follow of plus. And we already know what the first of E was. That was an open
跟在加号后面。我们已经知道E的第一个是什么了。那是一个空档
[inaudible], An int, Okay. And remember also that E cannot go to Epsilon. So, E
[听不见]，一个整数，好的。还要记住E不能去Epsilon。所以，E
cannot ever disappear completely because T always produces at least one terminal.
不可能完全消失，因为T总是至少产生一个终端。
Therefore, only the things that are in the first of year in the follow of plus.
因此，只有在第一年的事情是在加号之后。
Because E can't go to Epsilon, we only have to include the things that are in the
因为E不能去Epsilon，我们只需要包括在
first of E, in the follow of plus. Again, if you think about it for a minute this
第一个是E，后面是加号。再说一次，如果你想一分钟，这是
makes complete sense. What could come after a plus? Well, it could be an
完全有道理。加了之后会发生什么呢？嗯，这可能是一个
integer, the second argument to an addition, or it could be the beginning of
整数，加法的第二个参数，也可以是
another nested expression. And it couldn't be a times. It certainly couldn't be the
另一个嵌套表达式。它不可能是一个时代。当然不可能是
end of the input cuz you always have to have an argument after the plus. And, >>
输入的末尾，因为你总是必须在加号后面有一个参数。并且，>>
And I think that's it. I think that's all the other possibilities. >> Okay, Alright.
我想就是这样了。我想这就是所有其他的可能性了。>>好的，好的。
Now let's take a look at the follow of times. What can come after a times. Where
下面我们来看一下时间。一段时间后会发生什么。哪里
is times used, it's used here. So things that are in the first of t. Are gonna be
用的是时间，这里用的是时间。所以第一部分的内容将会是
in the follow of times again, alright? [inaudible] we already know what that is.
在接下来的时间里再来一次，好吗？[听不见]我们已经知道那是什么了。
That's the same as the first of E. That's open paren and ints. And again, this makes
这与E的第一个相同，也就是开放的Paren和INT。再一次，这使得
complete sense. What can come after a times? It's either the beginning of
完全有意义。一次之后会发生什么呢？要么就是这场战争的开始
another [inaudible] expression or an integer. It's certainly not a plus or the
另一个[听不见的]表达式或整数。这肯定不是一个好消息，也不是一个好消息。
end of the input, okay? And again, T cannot go to epsilon, and so that's the
输入结束，好吗？再说一次，T不能去ε，所以这就是
only thing. Those are the only things that can be in the follow of times. And now we
只有一件事。这些是唯一可以在接下来的时代中出现的东西。现在我们
just have one more symbol to go. We have to look at the follow of an integer, of an
只剩下一个标志了。我们必须看一个整数的后面，一个
int. Okay, where is that used in the grammar? Well, it's right here, Alright.
内部好的，这句话在语法中用在哪里？嗯，就在这里，好的。
So the, what's gonna be in the follow [inaudible], what 's going to include
那么，接下来(听不见)会有什么，会包括什么呢？
everything in the first of Y. Okay. What's in the first of Y, well times was in the
一切都在Y的第一个。好的。Y的第一个字母是什么，时间在字母Y的第一个字母中
first of Y, and epsilon was in the first of Y but remember, we don't include
在Y的第一个，ε在Y的第一个，但是记住，我们不包括
epsilons in follow sets. So, Y contributes times to the follow of int. But now,
下面几组中的爱普西隆。所以，Y为int的后面贡献了时间。但现在，
because Y could go to the epsilon and epsilon could [inaudible], that means that
因为Y可以到达epsilon，而epsilon可以[听不见]，这意味着
this int could wind up being at the right end of this production. Okay, it could,
这个int可能最终会成为这部作品的正确结局。好吧，有可能，
the Y could disappear and then whatever could follow the T could also follow the
Y可以消失，然后T后面的任何东西也可以跟着
int. Right, so we have to include the things in the follow of T. In the follow
内部对，所以我们必须把T后面的东西包括在后面
of it, and what was in the follow of T where that was a plus. It was a dollar.
以及紧随其后的是什么，这是一个加号。是一美元。
And it was a close paren, okay? And what does that tell us? Well it tells us, okay
这是一个势均力敌的朋友，好吗？这说明了什么呢？它告诉我们，好吗？
for most anything to follow an int but as an open paren cannot follow an int. So you
对于大多数跟在int后面的东西来说，除了作为一个开放的Paren之外，它不能跟在int后面。所以你
can't have another nesit expression with a, begin right after an int without an
不能有另一个带有a的嵌套表达式，在没有a的int之后立即开始
intervening operator, Alright? And that completes the computation of the follow
介入操作员，好吗？这就完成了下面的计算
sets for this example.
为本例设置。